[{"question":"<p><strong>What is the largest inland lake in South America?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ontario","Honshu","Titicaca","Amazon"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is heartsease?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A flower","A star","A stone","A snail"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What percentage of all the marriages in the world are arranged:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10%","30%","60%","90%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The French Tennis Open is played at which venue?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rod Claver","Marseille","Nice","Roland Garros"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which city is a Midsummer Nights Dream set?<br \/><\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Lyon","London","Athens","Venice"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which Greek king turned all he touched into gold?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["George IV","Napoleon","Midas","Cesar"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What name is given to a triangular or fanlike river?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Peninsular","Delta","Estuary","Coral reef"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which country did fireworks originate?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["England","Canada","USA","China"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When did the Bronze Age begin?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["1900 AD","200 AD","4500 BC","2000 BC"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the chemical symbol for silver?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Ag","Sn","Pb","Hg"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What name is given to the fruit of an oak tree ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Blackberry","Plum","Acorn","Strawberry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What name is given to the vertical bar of a window ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Eave","Sill","Mullion","Facia"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the name of the controversial novel that was written by Salmon Rushdie ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Angel of Doom","The Satanic Verses","On the Heels of Heavenly Virgins","The Lost Verses"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many kilograms are there in ten tonnes ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10000","1100","20000","14"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Does &lsquo;annus mirabilis&rsquo; mean:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A pain in the bum","A wonderful year","A horrible year","A leaking anus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which city does the White Nile meet the Blue Nile?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Juba","Alexandria","Khartoum","Cairo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the collective name for a litter of Piglets?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A farrow","A pen","A piggy","A sty"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What measure is used for sound or noise?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cacophony","Din","Decibels","Chaos"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many teeth should a normal healthy adult have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40","32","33","46"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which desert is the driest on earth?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Atacama","Kalahari","Sahara","Namib"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which precious stones are found in the Namib desert in Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Diamonds","Gold","Sapphire","Topaz"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In 1988, how many Chinese lived in caves?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["500,000","5,000,000","35,000,000","100,000,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which organ of the body is Insulin produced?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Heart","Pancreas","Liver","Kidney"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Where were the 1992 Winter Olympics held?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Albertville, France","Marseille, France","Ottawa, Canada","Ontario, Canada"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which century was Joan of Arc burnt at the stake?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15th Century","14th Century","13th Century","12th Century"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How is it known when a new Pope has been elected?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The death of the former Pope is announced","The Pope\u0092s Valet goes on air","White smoke comes out of the Vatican chimney","The bell of Saint Peter\u0092s Basilica sounds three times"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the meaning of the Latin phrase prima facie?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Qualified","At first sight","On this basis","At the primary level"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which sport is played in a Velodrome?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Wrestling","Boxing","Cycling","Pole vault"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which vitamin is produced by the action of ultraviolet light on the skin?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A","B","C","D"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the capital of Paraguay?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Asuncion","Del Potro","Havana","Puerto Rico"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many times was Franklin D. Roosevelt elected US president?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","4","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Hymen was the Greek god of what?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["War","Marriage","Love","Light"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the Decalogue usually called?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Decathlon","The Ten Commandments","The Last man standing","The Vatican\u0092s 10th Cardinal"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the Decalogue usually called?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Decathlon","The Ten Commandments","The Last man standing","The Vatican\u0092s 10th Cardinal"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What does a somnambulist do?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sleepwalks","Hallucinates","Duncan","Macbeth"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is Harley Davidson famous for manufacturing?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bicycles","Motor Cycles","Motorised mowers","Mercedes Benz engines"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the French national anthem called?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Le Marseillaise","The spangled omen","God save the Qeen","Freedom song"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who wrote a brief history of time?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Albert Einstein","Leonardo de Vinci","George Bell","Stephen Hawkins"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which movie studio has a roaring lion as its company symbol?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Columbia","Roaring Lion","MGM","BG"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If you were at Geneva airport, in which country would you be?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sweden","Switzerland","Austria","Norway"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the middle of a frequency distribution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Median","Mode","Medium","Statistics"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What describes an angle between 90 and 180 degrees?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acute","Obtuse","Oblong","Right angle"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What are the American universities Yale, Harvard and Princetown collectively known as?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Red bricks","Ivy League","Ivory Tower","High Society"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the only Country through which both the equator and the tropic of Capricorn pass?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["England","Thailand","Central African Republic","Brazil"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which metal is liquid at room temperature?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mercury","Iron","Aluminium","Chromium"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the third planet from the sun?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Earth","Neptune","Mars","The Moon"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the only English anagram of the word SECTIONAL<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Actionals","Coastline","Lionstal","Sectlion"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What do ichthyologists study?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Birds","Gnomes","Fish","Paedophiles"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What happens to Pinocchio every time he tells a lie?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["He loses a hair","His face reddens","His tongue protrudes","His nose grows larger"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was the Roman god of war?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mars","Venus","Poseidon","Prometheus"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the name of the people, language and culture of Madagascar?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Malay","Malabi","Malagasy","Madagascois"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An underground layer of porous rock that contains water is called what?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lithograph","Aquifer","Hydrofoil","Level"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In June 2009, which ruler began his second decade as king of Morocco?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Mohammed VI","Hassan I","Abdullah II","Al-Mustafa III"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What does the word \"dinosaur\" mean?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Huge creature","Great dragon","Terrible lizard","Enfant terrible"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Born with the last name Ayew, which striker is the top international scorer for Ghana?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abedi Pele","Samuel Kuffor","Daniel Amokachi","Kanu Nwankwo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which lead singer of Queen was born in Zanzibar?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Freddie Mercury","George Harrison","David Bowie","Gustav Dottie"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who wrote \"Wuthering Heights\"?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Emily Bronte","Patrick Branwell","Agatha Christie","Justine Henine"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which major trading bloc has Swaziland, Angola and Egypt among its members?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["PTA","SADC","COMESA","PAC"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which geological event occurs when tectonic plates slide and the ground shakes?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lightning","Ice Shelf formation","Earthquake","Tsunami"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which career are the terms \"defense mechanism\" and \"paranoia\" used?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Linguistics","Medicine","Psychology","Computer Engineering"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which year did a new constitution end apartheid in South Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1977","1994","1856","1999"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In February 2008, Mizengo Pinda became Prime Minister of which nation?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tanzania","Uganda","Kenya","Burundi"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Slate is which type of rock that has been changed by extreme heat and pressure?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sedimentary","Metamorphic","Soft","Megamorphic"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Whom did Muhammad Ali fight against in the 1974 \"Rumble in the Jungle\" ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["George Foreman","David Haye","Oscar De La Hoya","Joe Louis"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Where do the Niger, Gambia and Senegal rivers all have their source?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bambouk Mountains, Mali","Air Mountains, Niger","Fouta Djallon, Guinea","Futa Mountains"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who led the Central African Republic to independence in 1960?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Jean-Bedel Bokassa","Francois Bozize","David Dacko","Patrice Lumumba"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Libya, the Central African Republic and Sudan all border which other country?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chad","Mali","Nigeria","Benin"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In 2009, Pakistan began an offensive to reclaim which valley from the Taliban?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Beqaa","Swat","Ganges","Mumbai"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was Gabriel Daniel Fahrenheit?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["German Physicist","An American Geologist","Man who developed temperature scale","Man who developed the mercury thermometer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Galileo was an Italian astronomer who:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Discovered that the movement of the pendulum produces a regular time measurement","Discovered 4 satellites of Jupiter","Developed the telescope","All the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Committee of the Norwegian Parliament awards the Nobel Prize for:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Economics","Peace","Medicine","Literature"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences awards the Nobel prizes in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Physics","Economics","Chemistry","(a) and (d)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Kabul is the capital of which troubled country<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Albania","Andorra","Angola","Afghanistan"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Banjul is the capital of which of the following countries<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Gambia","Sene-gambia","Mali","Senegal"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many tentacles does an Octopus have?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["20","14","8","6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was the goddess of Love in Roman mythology?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Venus","Aphrodite","Promeus","Prometheus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who was the goddess of Love in Greek mythology?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Venus","Aphrodite","Promeus","Prometheus"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The only city in the world to lie between 2 continents is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ankara","Istanbul","Alexandria","Constantinople"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The acronym DVD stands for:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Digital Video Disc","Disque Vidoe Digitale","Digital Versatile Disc","Double Vidoe Density"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is a group of lions called?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Flock","Pride","Herd","Pack"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which planet is nearest to the sun?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mercury","Venus","Jupiter","Vulcan"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who among the following was the first to set foot on the Moon?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fran Phipps","Neil Alden Armstrong","Yuri Gagarin","Alexei Leonov"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The renowned author of the Harry Porter series is:<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Chimamanda Adichie","J.K.Rowling","John Milton","Chinua Achebe"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first Black person to be awarded the Nobel Peace Prize was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ralph Johnson Bunche","Professor Wole Soyinka","Bishop Desmond Tutu","President Julius Nyerere"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which character created by Washington Irving fell asleep for 20 years?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Robin Hood","Rip Van Winkle","Scarlet Fever","Valhalla"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What name is given to magic used with evil intent?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Blue","Black","White","Yellow"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What was the Greek hero Achilles only vulnerable part?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["His Nose","His Foot","His Heel","His Heart"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which planet has the highest surface temperature?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mars","Earth","Venus","Sun"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the fastest of all birds?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Black Vulture","African Eagle","White Owl","Perigrine Falcon"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the heaviest of all human organs?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Heart","Lungs","Skin","Liver"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What male singing voice comes below tenor?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tenor","Bass","Baritone","Alto"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which continent is Israel situated?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Asia","Africa","Europe","America"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which North African city has a name meaning \"White House \" in Spanish?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alexandria","Casablanca","Tripoli","Algiers"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many feet are in a fathom?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["9","12","6","3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many points are there to the compass?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["44","32","23","61"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who wrote the book Gulliver&rsquo;s Travels?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shakespeare","Charles Dickens","Salman Rushdie","Jonathan Swift"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which fruit contains the most calories?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Avocado Pear","Raspberry","Apple","Apple"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What was the capital of Russia before Moscow?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Leningrad","St Petersburg","Sovietville","Siberia"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which grain is used to make malt whiskey?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Leningrad","Barley","Sorghum","Maize"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>On the flag of which country would you find the most stars?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brazil","USA","North Korea","Sudan"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Between 1820 and 1900, the majority of immigrants to the USA came from which two countries?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Germany and Ireland","England and France","Germany and Scotland","Israel and Australia"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the most northerly city in the world?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Seoul, Korea","Ulan Bator, Mongolia","Hammerfest, Norway","Reykjavik, Iceland"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which European country has the highest tax rate?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Denmark","Sweden","Ireland","Germany"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which two countries share the longest border in the world, around 6,400km?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Canada and USA","Great Britain and Netherlands","Portugal and Spain","Morocco and Algeria"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following countries is NOT on the shores of Lake Victoria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Uganda","Rwanda","Kenya","Tanzania"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the name of the deepest lake in Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lake Victoria","Lake Tanganyika","Lake Tanganyika","Lake Congo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Tanzania is the only country in the world with a unique gemstone called:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gemstan","Columbite","Tanzanite","Soladite"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In West Africa is a Lake shared by 4 countries. What is this Lake called:<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Bongo","Chad","Victoria","Tanganyika"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 4 countries that share the Lake Chad are one of the following sets:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["DR Congo, Tanzania, Kenya and Uganda","Tanzania, Uganda, Malawi and Rwanda","Niger, Nigeria, Cameroon and Chad","Chad, Mali, Ghana and Cameron"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The River Nile takes its source from one of these countries:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Egypt","Sudan","Kenya","Uganda"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which country is singer Angelique Kidjo from?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghana","South Africa","Nigeria","Benin"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Zimbabwe attained Independence in the year:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1975","1979","1980","1981"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>World War II commenced in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1930","1935","1939","1940"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>World War 1 started in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1904","1908","1910","1914"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which country suffered the heaviest in World War II?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["France","Germany","Japan","England"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which part of the world is named after the goddess of winter and the hunt?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Greenland","Scandinavia","The Arctic","Mongolia"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Greek mythology, who was responsible for slaying the Amazon queen Penthesilea?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Artemis","Zeus","Prometheus","Achilles"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What does the lachrymal sac hold?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tears","Blood","Juice","Gas"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which poem deals with the events surrounding the Trojan War?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Odyssey","Iliad","Sonnet","Epigram"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which synthetic food was named by its inventor after the Greek word for pearl?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tuber","Cereal","Noodle","Margarine"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What type of foodstuff is sorghum, used as a staple diet in Africa and parts of Asia<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tuber","Cereal","Grain","Fruit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An excursion for pleasure made by an official at the expense of the tax payer<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Safari","Junket","Sabbatical","Awol"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is a sculptural representation of a person from the chest up?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Soliloquy","Kiln","Bust","Image"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A caldera is found at the top of which of these?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A giraffe","A train","A volcano","A peacock"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The word \"burning\" in the phrase \"a burning candle\" is which type of word?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Conjunction","Adjective","Preposition","Verb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Goree, Bunce, Lamu and Robben are which kind of natural feature?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Islands","Lakes","Highlands","Mountains"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Peanut and alfalfa plants contain bacteria that add which nutrient to soil?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Argon","Potassium","Nitrogen","Oxygen"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The war of American Independence was fought between:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["North America and South America","Britain and North America","France and America","North America and Canada"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Capitalism is characterised by all below EXCEPT:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The elimination of financial risks","Private ownership","Making profit","The laws of supply and demand"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not correct about the African National Congress (ANC)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Was formed to fight apartheid in South Africa","Was accused by the government of Communist leanings","Was a liberation movement","Was supported by US and UK in the years leading to Independence"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following helps in clotting of blood?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Vitamin B1","Vitamin B2","Vitamin D","Vitamin K"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The total volume of blood in a normal adult human being is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5 - 6 litres","3 - 4 litres","8 - 10 litres","10 - 12 litres"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Red blood corpuscles are formed where?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Liver","Bone marrow","kidneys","Heart"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many bones are there in an adult human being?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["210","260","206","300"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Tibia is a bone in the human:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Skull","Arm","Leg","Face"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The largest part of the human brain is the:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Medulla oblongata","Cerebellum","Cerebrum","None"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main function of the kidney is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["To control blood pressure","To control body temperature","To remove waste product from the body","To help in digestion of food"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the largest gland in the human body?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Thyroid","Liver","Pancreas","None"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the only country that borders the White Sea?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Iceland","Norway","Russia","Japan"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>On what continent would you find the Republic of Mauritania?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Asia","Africa","America","Europe"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Muscat is the capital city of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oman","Bahrain","Quatar","Kuwait"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which US state is known as the Sunshine State?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["New York","Rhode Island","Florida","Ondo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which country was the city of Natal (\"Christmas\") founded on 25th December 1599?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brazil","Israel","Italy","Saudi Arabia"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the least populated country in the world?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gambia","Iceland","The Vatican City","Somaliland"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the largest country in Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Sudan","Nigeria","South Africa","Iraq"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which country has four cities in the list of the ten hottest cities in the world? <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mali","India","Sudan","Yemen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which city would you find the largest Japanese community outside of Japan ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Toronto","Sao Paulo","Miami","D.Melbourne"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is the Roman god of wine?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Orpheus","Bacchus","Guinness","Romulus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which country was the last to occupy a United States territory with its soldiers?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Great Britain","Japan","France","Ireland"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>While Rome was burning in 64AD, Nero allegedly was playing on his<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lyre","Fiddle","Flute","Sitar"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which Christian order did St. Ignatius of Loyola found in 1534?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dominican Order","Jesuit Order","White Fathers Order","Loyola Order"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Before becoming President of the USA, Ronald Reagan was governor of which US state?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["New York","New Orleans","Virginia","California"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which US state was NOT one of the 13 colonies that signed the Declaration of Independence in 1776:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["New York .","Virginia","Massachusetts","Kansas"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which period in the development of human culture did not exist:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brass Age","Bronze Age","Iron Age","Copper Age"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In what country did Che Guevara die on 9th October 1967?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Peru","Colombia","Venezuela","Bolivia"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Since March 1959, the Dalai Lama had lived in exile in which country?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Russia","India","China","Pakistan"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which war was officially ended by the Treaty of Versailles?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["World War I","World War II","American War of Independence","Korean War"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which people created the Cuneiform script:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Babylonians","Egyptians","Assyrians","Sumerians"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which country was OPEC founded in 1960:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["USA","Iraq","Venezuela","Kuwait"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>On 6th October of what year was Egyptian president Muhammad Anwar al-Sadat assassinated?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1969","1973","1981","1988"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>On 26th December of what year was the USSR officially dissolved?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1956","1976","1991","1989"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A production possibility curve shows<\/strong><\/p>","options":["How much of the resources of society are used to produce a particular commodity     D\t.The various combination of two commodities that can be produced.","The rate of inflation","The rate of unemployment in the economy","The various combination of two commodities that can be produced."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following best describes the concept of opportunity cost?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A special bargain or sale at below market price","Costs for inputs tend to go up as we use more of them","Goods that are not produced in order to produce more of another good.","A cost that constantly decreases."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choice in economic life is necessitated by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The need to construct scale of preference","The opportunity cost of consumption","Unlimited wants","Scarcity of economic resources."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"}]